Sabean, Harrison J.

Scituate, MA | 781-690-8994 | <u>hsabes@gmail.com</u> <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>Github</u> | <u>Blog</u> | <u>Code Wars</u> | <u>Portfolio</u>

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Software Engineer whose passion is to learn, build, and teach independently and alongside other talented developers. Experienced with front and backend development using languages, frameworks, and tools such as JavaScript, React, Ruby/Rails, SQL, Agile, CSS/MUI/Chakra-UI, and HTML5. With a background in education and first response, I am inspired by technology that lifts the world up.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

FlatApp Store - GitHub

FlatApp Store is a platform for students of Flatiron's Bootcamps to view other student's projects

- Collaborated in a team of three developers using GitHub for version control and backing up code
- Incorporated CSS framework Chakra-UI to build custom inline-CSS styling

Whiskker - GitHub

Users can create an account for their cat to post MeowPosts, add Catpanions (friends), and interact with other cats on the platform

- Shaped the Ruby on Rails backend with self-relational database tables to connect users
- Installed and executed Bcrypt to protect users' private information

Hmail - GitHub | Demo

Users can create an Hmail account and send emails to other Hmail users

- Learned and integrated Active Storage using PATCH requests for profile pictures
- Utilized Material-UI to create a responsive design that functions for users with smaller screens

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript, React.js, JQuery, PHP, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, HTML5, CSS/SCSS/ChakraUl/Material-Ul, CLI, PostgreSQL, SQL, relational databases, RESTful API, Active Record, Active Storage, Git, Postman

WORK EXPERIENCE

JackRabbit Design

Milton, MA

Web Development Intern

12/2022 - 03/2023

- Collaborated with developers, designers, and project managers to assist in the development of ongoing and upcoming projects.
- Created responsive, pixel perfect web pages using HTML, SCSS, and Javascript/JQuery according to the approved designs.
- Tackled complex and scalable Javascript/¡Query solutions for unique client requested designs.

Whitcom 911

Pullman, WA

Emergency 911 Call Taker and Dispatcher

04/2021 - 03/2022

- Dispatched calls to appropriate personnel depending on individual call situations for Whitman County, WA jurisdiction servicing over 100,000 citizens.
- Operated six computers, four speakers, one headset, and multiple calls and radio traffic at once.

Science Museum of Minnesota

St. Paul, MN

Visitor Experience Associate

08/2015 - 07/2019

- Directed clients to appropriate personnel to address concerns, resolve complaints or answer account-related questions.
- Greeted customers, answered gallery questions and directed to appropriate locations.

EDUCATION

EDUCATION	
Flatiron School Full Stack Software Engineering, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript/React program	Online 05/2022 - 08/2022
Washington State University Graduate Studies in Music Education	Pullman, WA 08/2019 - 12/2020
Berklee College of Music BPS in Guitar	Online 01/2018 - 12/2018
McNally Smith College of Music BM in Guitar Performance	St. Paul, MN 08/2014 - 12/2017